<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>visual world paradigm on Violet Brown</title>
    <link>/tags/visual-world-paradigm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in visual world paradigm on Violet Brown</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/visual-world-paradigm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Where are the Fixations?:&#34; Grammatical Number Cues Guide Anticipatory Fixations to Upcoming Referents and Reduce Lexical Competition</title>
      <link>/publications/brown_fox_strand_2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publications/brown_fox_strand_2021/</guid>
      <description>Listeners make use of contextual cues during continuous speech processing that help overcome the limitations of the acoustic input. These semantic, grammatical, and pragmatic cues facilitate prediction of upcoming words and/or reduce the lexical search space by inhibiting activation of contextually inappropriate words that share phonological information with the target. The current study used the visual world paradigm to assess whether and how listeners use contextual cues about grammatical number during sentence processing by presenting target words in carrier phrases that were grammatically unconstraining (&amp;rsquo;&amp;ldquo;Click on the .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keep Listening: Grammatical Context Reduces But Does Not Eliminate Activation of Unexpected Words</title>
      <link>/publications/strand_etal_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publications/strand_etal_2017/</guid>
      <description>To understand spoken language, listeners combine acoustic-phonetic input with expectations derived from context (Dahan &amp;amp; Magnuson, 2006). Eye-tracking studies on semantic context have demonstrated that the activation levels of competing lexical candidates depend on the relative strengths of the bottom-up input and top-down expectations (cf. Dahan &amp;amp; Tanenhaus, 2004). In the grammatical realm, however, graded effects of context on lexical competition have been predicted (Magnuson, Tanenhaus, &amp;amp; Aslin, 2008), but not demonstrated.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
