<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tutorial on Violet Brown</title>
    <link>https://www.violetabrown.com/tags/tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tutorial on Violet Brown</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.violetabrown.com/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Preregistration: Practical Considerations for Speech, Language, and Hearing Research</title>
      <link>https://www.violetabrown.com/publications/brown_strand_2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.violetabrown.com/publications/brown_strand_2023/</guid>
      <description>In the last decade, psychology and other sciences have implemented numerous reforms to improve the robustness of our research, many of which are based on increasing transparency throughout the research process. Among these reforms is the practice of preregistration, in which researchers create a time- stamped and uneditable document before data collection that describes the methods of the study, how the data will be analyzed, the sample size, and many other decisions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spread the Word: Enhancing Replicability of Speech Research Through Stimulus Sharing</title>
      <link>https://www.violetabrown.com/publications/strand_brown_2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.violetabrown.com/publications/strand_brown_2023/</guid>
      <description>Purpose: The ongoing replication crisis within and beyond psychology has revealed the numerous ways in which flexibility in the research process can affect study outcomes. In speech research, examples of these “researcher degrees of freedom” include the particular syllables, words, or sentences presented; the talkers who produce the stimuli and the instructions given to them; the population tested; whether and how stimuli are matched on amplitude; the type of masking noise used and its presentation level; and many others.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Linear Mixed-Effects Modeling in R</title>
      <link>https://www.violetabrown.com/publications/brown_2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.violetabrown.com/publications/brown_2021/</guid>
      <description>This Tutorial serves as both an approachable theoretical introduction to mixed-effects modeling and a practical introduction to how to implement mixed-effects models in R. The intended audience is researchers who have some basic statistical knowledge, but little or no experience implementing mixed-effects models in R using their own data. In an attempt to increase the accessibility of this Tutorial, I deliberately avoid using mathematical terminology beyond what a student would learn in a standard graduate-level statistics course, but I reference articles and textbooks that provide more detail for interested readers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Speech amid the Jingle and Jangle: Recommendations for Improving Measurement Practices in Listening Effort Research</title>
      <link>https://www.violetabrown.com/publications/strand_etal_2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.violetabrown.com/publications/strand_etal_2021/</guid>
      <description>The latent constructs psychologists study are typically not directly accessible, so researchers must design measurement instruments that are intended to provide insights about those constructs. Construct validation—assessing whether instruments measure what they intend to—is therefore critical for ensuring that the conclusions we draw actually reflect the intended phenomena. Insufficient construct validation can lead to the jingle fallacy—falsely assuming two instruments measure the same construct because the instruments share a name—and the jangle fallacy—falsely assuming two instruments measure different constructs because the instruments have different names.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publishing Open, Reproducible Research With Undergraduates</title>
      <link>https://www.violetabrown.com/publications/strand_brown_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.violetabrown.com/publications/strand_brown_2019/</guid>
      <description>In response to growing concern in psychology and other sciences about low rates of replicability of published findings (Open Science Collaboration, 2015), there has been a movement toward conducting open and transparent research (see Chambers, 2017). This has led to changes in statistical reporting guidelines in journals (Appelbaum et al., 2018), new professional societies (e.g., Society for the Improvement of Psychological Science), frameworks for posting materials, data, code, and manuscripts (e.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
